All right!
太棒了
Yes! From home to the hospital in under seven minutes! We did it.
从家里赶到医院 花了不到七分钟的时间，我们办到了
Yes, the hard part is truly over.
对，最难的部份完成了
No, but come on, we're off to a great start, aren't we?
不，但打起精神来 我们有个不错的开始，对吧？
I knew I'd get here fast, but this has gotta be some kind of a record!
我知道我可以很快赶到这里 但这一定是创下了记录
-Oh, you made it! -Hi.
-你们赶到了 -嗨
-How the hell did you beat us here? -We took a cab. Did you guys walk?
-你们怎么会比我们先到？ -我们搭计程车，你们是走过来的吗？
No, we took a cab too. But I did test runs..
不，我们也是搭计程车 但我做过实验…
Hey, you made it!
你们赶到了
Okay, is there some kind of magic tunnel to this hospital?
好吧，难不成有魔法地道 通到这家医院？
Ross, you stay here and talk. I'm gonna go have a baby.
罗斯，你留下来聊天 我要去生孩子了
Okay. Hi, this is Rachel Greene. I'm Ross Geller. We called from the car.
好吧，她是瑞秋葛林 我是罗斯盖勒，我们在车上打过电话
Right. We have a semi-private labor room waiting for you, so..
对，我们为你们准备了 双人待产室，所以…
Oh, whoa! I'm sorry. Semi-private? We asked for a private room.
对不起，双人房？ 我们订了单人房
Yes, I see that here. Unfortunately, we can't guarantee a private room.
我知道，不幸地是 我们无法保证一定有单人房
-And, currently, they're all unavailable. -Man, if only you'd gotten here sooner.
-现在单人房都满了 -你该快点过来的
I'm sorry. Semi-private rooms are all we have.
抱歉 我们只有双人待产室
Okay. Just give us a second. Ross?
好吧，等一下，罗斯
Yeah?
什么？
-Give her some money. -I really think they're out of rooms.
-塞点钱给她 -我真的相信他们没房间了
They're not, Ross. They're just saving them for important people!
才怪，罗斯 他们为大人物保留房间
Okay? What if I was the president?
好吧？如果我是总统呢？
Well, then, we'd be in a lot of trouble. You don't know where any countries are.
那么我们麻烦大了 你不知道任何国家的地理位置
Okay.
好吧
Say, would you mind checking again?
你能再帮我们看看吗？
See if any private rooms may have opened up?
有没有我们可以使用的 单人待产室？
This is a hospital.
这里是医院
Okay, I see. Could we please talk to the manager?
我懂了 我们能跟经理谈一谈吗？
There is no manager.
这里没有经理
Just nurses, doctors and semi-private rooms.
只有护士、医生 跟双人待产室
Okay, you know what? I have to say, I don't really care for your tone.
好吧，你知道吗？我得说 我真的不在乎你的语气
And this is not the only hospital in this city, and we have no problem.. Oh, gosh!
这是市里唯一一家医院 我们没有问题…天啊
-What? What? -Contraction!
-什么？ -是阵痛
-Would you like to see a semi-private room? -Yeah, it couldn't hurt to look.
-你们想看看双人待产室吗？ -好吧，看看又何妨
The One Where Rachel Has A Baby
本集播出：瑞秋生产记
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
Well, you're only two centimeters dilated, and we need to get to 10.
你只开了两公分 得等到开十公分才行
-It'll be a while. -Oh, okay.
-那得等上一段时间 -好吧
-I'll be back in an hour to check you again. -Thank you.
-我一小时后再回来帮你检查 -谢谢
Oh, wait, Dr. Long. Can I ask you something?
等一下，朗医生 我能问你一件事吗？
Is labor really as painful as everybody says it is?
生产真的跟大家说的一样 那么痛吗？
Oh, look at that. My beeper's going crazy.
天啊 我的呼叫器响个不停
Hey, don't.. You know what? You're gonna be fine.
别…你知道吗？ 你会没事的
-I guess we have some time to kill. -Yeah, guess so.
-我猜我们得想办法杀时间 -没错
Oh, check these out.
你看
Never done this before.
我从来没有这么做过
Doesn't feel good.
不觉得很舒服
Yeah, well, it looks great.
对，它看起来很不错
Thank you very much. I think we're ready to..
谢谢 我想我们准备好…
Hi, I'm Ross. I'm here to ruin this magical day for you.
嗨，我是罗斯 我来帮你们毁了这美好的一天
Oh, no, not at all. It's okay. Marc Horger. This is my wife, Julie.
一点都不会，没关系的，马克何格 她是我太太茱莉
-Hi, Julie. This is Rachel. -Oh, hi, Rachel.
-嗨，茱莉，她是瑞秋 -嗨，瑞秋
-Is this your first? -Yeah, it is.
-这是你的第一胎？ -对
Well, little Jamie here is our third.
小吉米是我们的第三胎
So if you have any questions, or you need anything at all, just holler.
如果你们有问题 或需要帮忙，叫我们一声
-That's so sweet. -Yeah.
-那真的是太棒了 -对
-Let me give you guys some privacy. -Nonsense. We're all in this together.
-我得让你们独处下 -没关系，我们可以一起来
We are gonna share every moment of this with you.
我们愿意 跟你们分享每一刻
-I think we're gonna have some fun. -Yeah.
-我想我们会非常愉快 -对
-Oh, okay, I guess. -Hey, smile!
-好吧 -笑一个
-I don't know if.. -I really don't want any..
-我不知道… -我真的不要…
Oh, thank you.
谢谢
Oh, Ross! Here comes another contraction.
罗斯 我又开始阵痛了
Okay, just breathe.
好吧，深呼吸
-Oh, honey, I think I'm having one too! -Oh, my God!
-甜心，我想我也开始阵痛了 -天啊
Hey, look at this.
你看
-Here you go! -Oh, no!
-来吧 -不
Oh, wow. Three hours and still no baby.
三个小时还是没生
The miracle of birth sure is a snooze-fest.
生产的奇迹 的确让人很想打瞌睡
-Hey, you wanna see something? -Sure. What?
-你要看看好玩的事吗？ -当然要，什么？
This is gonna be fun. Watch me freak out Chandler.
这一定会很好玩 看我怎么吓钱德
-Honey? -Yeah?
-甜心 -什么？
Listen, I've been doing some thinking..
听着 我一直在想…
and I don't know whether it's because we're here..
我不知道是因为 我们来到这里…
or Rachel's giving birth..
或是瑞秋要生孩子…
but I think we should try to have a baby.
但我想我们应该试着怀孕
Okay.
好吧
What's that now?
你说什么？
Okay. I've been thinking about it too, and I think we're ready.
好吧，我也一直在想那件事 我想我们准备好了
Are you kidding? You think we're ready to have a baby now?
你在开玩笑吗？ 你觉得我们准备好要怀孕了？
This is fun.
这真的很好玩
You're ready to have a baby? My boy's all grown up!
你们准备要怀孕了？ 我的小男孩长大了
You said you were ready too.
你说你也准备好了
Yeah, but I was just screwing with you to try to get your voice all high and weird..
对，我只是想跟你开玩笑 让你用高八度的怪声音说话…
Like mine is now!
就像我现在一样
Yes, but haven't you wanted a kid, like, forever?
对，但你不是一直 都想要生孩子吗？
Yeah, but no one ever wanted to have one with me. I mean..
对，但没有人 想跟我生孩子，我是说…
Now I'm just gonna have a baby if I want to. Oh, what are you doing to me?
如果我要的话，我要生个孩子 你对我做了什么？
I'm sorry I brought it up.
抱歉我提起这件事
Okay, then, back off, mister!
好吧，滚开，先生
Because I am ready to have a baby.
因为我准备生孩子了
I just want Joey to be the father.
我只是希望乔伊是孩子的爸
-What? Are you crazy? -That's it, right there! That's all I wanted!
-什么？你疯了吗？ -就是那样，那就是我的目的
I am sorry. The doctor insisted on closing the curtain for the exam.
抱歉，医生坚持 拉上幕布做检查
Oh, that's very.. Really, very, very okay.
那非常… 真的没关系
Julie's cervix is dilated seven centimeters. That's about four fingers!
茱莉的子宫颈开了七公分 大约是四指宽
-Doctor let me feel it myself. -Have you felt Rachel's cervix, Ross?
-医生让我自己摸摸看 -你摸过瑞秋的子宫颈吗？罗斯
-No, I don't.. We're not gonna do that. -We won't be doing that.
-没有…我们不会那么做 -我们不会那么做
Well, if you like, you could feel Rachel's, then feel mine to compare.
如果你要的话，你可以摸摸瑞秋的 再摸摸我的做比较
-Am I interrupting? -Yes! Thank you! Later.
-我打扰了你们吗？ -太棒了，谢谢，待会见
-No, you can't leave me alone with them. -Oh, I'm sorry.
-不，你不能丢下我跟他们独处 -对不起
No, Ross? Ross? Ross? My child has no father!
不，罗斯 我的孩子没有父亲
I'm so glad you're here, but it's gonna be a while. I wish you'd called first.
我很高兴你来了 可能还要再等一下，你该先打电话来
That's all right. I'm coming back later with your father.
没关系 我待会会再跟你爸来一趟
-I needed to talk to you before the birth. -Okay. What's up?
-在孩子出生前我得跟你谈一谈 -好吧，什么事？
Ross, I want to talk to you as your mother..
罗斯，我得用妈妈的身份 跟你谈…
even though I know that you and I are also very close friends.
即使我知道 你跟我也是好朋友
I really don't know what you're talking about, but okay.
我真的不知道你在说什么 但没关系
I brought something that I want to give you.
我有样东西要给你
Assuming, of course, that you want it.
假设你真的要它
Ma, you're asking me to marry you?
妈，你要我娶你？
This is your grandmother's engagement ring, I want you to give it to Rachel.
这是你外婆的订婚戒指 我要你把它送给瑞秋
-Mom, no. Come on. Thank you. -Just hear me out..
-妈，不，别这样，谢谢你 -听我说…
No! Okay? We've been through this.
不，好吗？我们谈过了
We're not gonna get married just because she's pregnant. Okay?
我们不会因为她怀孕了 就去结婚，好吗？
Honestly, Ross, this isn't just some girl you picked up in a bar and humped.
说真的，罗斯 她不是你在酒吧泡到就上的女孩
You think young people use that word more than we actually do.
年轻人比我们 更常用那个字
Ross, a child should have a family.
罗斯，孩子应该要有家庭
You know what? I can't deal with this right now. I'm sorry.
你知道吗？ 我现在无法思考此事，抱歉
Go.. Hey, go talk to Monica.
去…去跟摩妮卡聊一聊
She got a new haircut. You'll hate it.
她换了新发型 你会讨厌的
Just think about it. If you don't, I'll talk more about humping.
考虑一下，如果你不那么做 我会再跟你谈上女孩的事
Give me.
给我吧
-Hi, dear. -Hi. Thank you so much for coming.
-嗨，亲爱的 -谢谢你赶过来
Ross, get in here!
罗斯，快进来
You wanna see something funny?
你想看好笑的事吗？
Monica.
摩妮卡
Okay. All right, stop it. You're freaking me out.
好吧，别闹了 你把我吓坏了
Do it again. Do it again.
再来一次
Hey, Rachel had the baby.
瑞秋生了
-What? -Really?
-什么？ -真的吗？
No.
不
I don't know why I thought that'd be funny.
我不知道为什么 我会觉得那很好笑
You said hi to Mom before she left, right?
妈走之前 你跟她打过招呼吧？
I thought that was her.
我就知道是她
Yeah, I called her name, and she ducked into a stairwell.
我叫了她 她躲进楼梯间里
Well, you know what? Consider yourself lucky.
你知道吗？你真的很幸运
She pulled me out of the labor room to ask me why I'm not with Rachel.
她把我拖出待产室 问我为什么不跟瑞秋结婚
-Oh, my God. -How annoying.
-天啊 -那一定很烦
Yeah.
对
-Why aren't you with Rachel? -You're kidding, right?
-你为什么不跟瑞秋结婚？ -你在开玩笑吗？
Look, we're not gonna be together just because we're having this baby.
我们不会因为孩子的关系 就去办结婚
And I know she's not just some girl I humped..
我知道她不是 我上过就算的女孩…
Oh, humped?
上过就算？
Come on, Ross.
少来了，罗斯
But it just seems that you two belong together.
但看起来 你们两个属于彼此
Okay, stop it. I can't deal with this right now. I have to go have a baby.
别说了，现在我无法想这件事 我得去等孩子出生
Right. And with who again?
对，你还要跟谁生孩子？
He's crazy. Why doesn't he wanna be with Rachel?
他疯了 他为什么不跟瑞秋结婚？
I know.
我知道
Seriously, she's like the perfect woman. I mean, I know she turned me down..
说真的她是个完美女性 我知道她拒绝了我…
but if she hadn't and she wanted to be with me..
如果她没有 她想跟我在一起…
I would take her in my arms and..
我会抱着她…
I haven't bummed you guys out like this in a while, have I?
我有一阵子 没有这样吓你们了吧？
-Hey. -Hey.
-嘿 -嘿
-Who's that? -New people.
-那是谁？ -新来的人
What happened to the Disgustingtons?
恶心夫妇怎么了？
They're having their baby. It's not fair, Ross. I got here first!
他们去生孩子了 那不公平，罗斯，是我先来的
Right after you left, they wheeled her off into delivery.
你离开不久 他们就将她推进产房了
Oh, but not before she gave me a nice, juicy shot of little Jamie crowning away.
但她走之前 让我看了一下她的产道
Wow. Sorry.
抱歉
So how are the new people?
新来的人怎么样？
Well, they have some unusual pet names for each other.
他们帮彼此 取了很不寻常的绰号
Including "Evil Bitch" and "Sick Bastard."
包括“坏心死人”跟“病态混蛋”
-Oh, gosh, a contraction. -Yeah? Okay, okay. Just breathe.
-天啊，是阵痛 -是吗？好了，深呼吸
-Are you looking at her? -No!
-你在看她吗？ -不
-Don't you look at her, you sick bastard! -Honey, I swear I wasn't looking at her!
-别看她，病态混蛋 -甜心，我发誓我没有看她
She's in labor. You like that, you sick son of a bitch?
她要生了 你喜欢吗？病态死人
I'm just gonna..
我只是…
See? It's because you were looking, you fat pervert.
看吧？那都是你偷看的关系 胖变态
No, no. I'm sure no one was looking. Just want some privacy.
不，我相信没有人在偷看 我们只是需要一点隐私
You miss your girlfriend?
你想念你的女朋友吗？
Just ignore them.
别理他们
-You okay? -Yeah.
-你没事吧？ -没事
-Ross. -What?
-罗斯 -什么？
-He's looking at me. -Hey!
-他在偷看我 -嘿
You wanna live to see your baby?
你想活着看到你的孩子吗？
Don't you talk to my husband like that, you stupid bastard!
别那样跟我说话 你这个大笨蛋
Oh, good God! If you want a baby so bad, just go steal it!
天啊，如果你那么想要孩子 去偷一个吧
Oh, don't worry. These babies are far too ugly for us.
别担心 对我们来说这些宝宝太丑了
What is going on with you. Since when are you so crazy about babies?
你是怎么了？ 你什么时候这么喜欢孩子了？
I'm not crazy about babies. I'm crazy about us.
我不是喜欢孩子 我是为我们感到疯狂
What?
什么？
We've always talked about having babies someday, not now..
我们总是说以后要生孩子 不是现在…
but I'm starting to think that we can handle it. We're good.
但我开始认为我们应付得来 我们准备好了
We're really good.
我们真的准备好了
We are pretty good.
我们准备齐全
But nothing has to happen until you're ready.
但你没准备好前 我是不会行动的
Well, maybe I'm ready now.
或许我准备好了
I mean, it's a little scary, but maybe it's right.
我是说它有点可怕 或许没关系
What? It's not right! We're not ready to have a kid now!
什么？才不会没关系 我们还没有准备好要生孩子
-What? -I'm kidding. This is gonna be fun.
-什么？ -我是在开玩笑，这一定会很好玩
So we're gonna try? I mean, we're trying?
我们要试试看吗？ 我们现在要试吗？
We're trying to get pregnant.
我们要试着怀孕
I'm not comfortable doing this in front of the babies.
我不想在宝宝面前 那么做
-So when do you want to start trying? -All right, hold on a sec.
-你想什么时候开始试？ -好吧，等一下
-Period math? -Yeah.
-你在算生理周期？ -对
Well, we could start trying now.
我们可以从现在开始
-Right here? -No, not here.
-在这里？ -不是
Maybe here.
或许吧
It's perfect. We got a lot of time to kill, and we're in a building that's full of beds!
这里很完美，我们得想办法杀时间 而且医院里有很多床
And it's so clean!
它还很干净
Come on, you stupid machine! Come on!
加油，你这个笨机器
-It ate your money? -No.
-它吃掉你的钱了吗？ -没有
-I'll see you downstairs then. -All right.
-那么楼下见 -好吧
Hey, I got one! I got one!
我拿到了
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨 -嗨
-Oh, up or down? -Oh. Down, please.
-上或下？ -下楼，谢谢
I hate to be a ball-buster, but can I just do it?
我讨厌抢男人的风头 但可以由我来吗？
-Could you press up too? -Sure.
-麻烦你按上楼 -没问题
-I feel bad. I broke my leg once too. -Yeah? How'd yours happen?
-我真的很遗憾，我也曾摔断过腿 -是吗？你怎么会摔断腿？
Well, it's a long story, it's kind of embarrassing.
说来话长 那有点丢脸
Let's just say there was a typographical error with a sex manual.
就说那是性爱手册 排版上出了点小错误
-How about you? -Car accident.
-你呢？ -车祸
Some idiot on a cell phone wasn't paying attention?
有个白痴在打手机 没注意看前面？
Yeah. Me.
对，就是我
-Sorry. -Oh, no. No, don't be.
-抱歉 -不，别那么说
Nobody else got hurt. And I was pretty lucky.
没有别人受伤 我非常幸运
Well, I, for one, am glad you made it.
我很高兴你没有大碍
Are you sure? I mean, you don't know me.
是吗？你并不认识我
I could have been sent from another planet to destroy Earth.
我可能是被派来 摧毁地球的外星人
Couldn't press the "down" button. I think Earth's okay.
你连“下楼”按钮都按不到 我想地球很安全
Oh, hey, that's me.
我的电梯来了
Hey, I take it you're just visiting someone.
我想你是来探病的
Well, if you have some time and you wanna visit someone else..
如果你有时间想拜访其他人…
Yeah, I would like that.
对，我很乐意
-Great. I'm in room.. -Wait! What? No! Elevator! No!
-太棒了，我的房号是… -等一下，什么？不，电梯
You gotta press the button.
你得按下按钮才行
The nurse said they're bringing in another woman.
护士说 他们要送另一位女人过来
Oh. Is she pregnant yet?
她怀孕了吗？
She doesn't need to be. She'll still have the baby before I do.
她不需要 她还是能比我更快将孩子生下来
-Oh, Ross! Another contraction. -Oh, okay. Here, here.
-罗斯，我又阵痛了 -好吧
That's it.
没错
-Oh, that sounded like a bad one. -Yeah, it was.
-听起来好像很痛 -没错
Mine haven't been so bad. Oh, here comes one now.
我的阵痛没有那么厉害 又来了
Oh, that was a big one.
真的好痛
That was, like, the biggest one yet. Are you okay, honey?
那像是最痛的一次 你没事吧？甜心
I'm okay, honey.
我没事
Well, I got some bad news. It gets worse.
我有坏消息 越来越痛了
And when you get to the end, they get really big..
到了最后 它们真的很痛…
and they come, like, every minute.
每分钟就会来个一次
Well, mine are pretty close together. I think..
我的阵痛间隔很短 我想…
-Excuse me. -Yeah, that's quite all right.
-对不起 -没关系
Oh, by the way, my name's Johanna. What's yours?
对了，我是乔安娜 你呢？
Excuse me, could you help me with something?
对不起，你能帮我一下吗？
I'm looking for a man.
我在找一个男人
Well, who isn't?
谁不是呢？
You. You aren't.
你不是
Good for you.
太好了
Anyway, the patient I'm looking for has a broken leg.
总之我在找 一个断了一条腿的病人
He's in a wheelchair. He's early to mid-30s, very attractive.
他坐着轮椅，31到35岁 非常迷人
Even you would think so.
连你都会那么想
-I know who you're talking about. -Great! What room number is he in?
-我知道你在说谁 -太棒了，他住几号病房？
I'm sorry. Patient information is confidential.
抱歉 我们得对病人的资料保密
No, I'm not gonna bother him. We were talking earlier..
我不会打扰他 我们刚刚说过话…
Ma'am, I'm sorry. That information is restricted to hospital staff.
小姐，对不起 只有医院人员能取得资料
-She's with me. Dr. Drake Ramoray. -Dr. Drake who?
-她跟我是一起的，德瑞克拉莫瑞医生 -哪个德瑞克医生？
Ramoray. It's Portuguese. We need that information. I'm a doctor.
拉莫瑞，那是葡萄牙姓 我们需要他的资料，我是医生
-A doctor at this hospital? -Damn it, we're losing precious time.
-这间医院的医生？ -该死，我们正在浪费宝贵的时间
You want this man's blood on your head..?
你希望头上 沾了这男人的血…
-Hands. -Hands!
-是手 -手上
It is absolutely essential that you tell me what room he is staying in.
你必须告诉我 他住几号病房
He's a patient of mine. I've treated him for years.
他是我的病人 我治疗他很多年了
-He's in room 816. -816. Thank you.
-他住816号病房 -816，谢谢
-And what is his name? -No.
-他叫什么名字？ -不
-I think we found a place. -Okay.
-我想我们找到一个地方了 -好吧
Wait. Wanna set the mood a little?
等一下，你想增加一点气氛吗？
Hello, Monica.
哈，摩妮卡
-Not like that. -Oh, okay.
-不是那样 -好吧
-We'll dim the lights. -Okay.
-把灯关了 -好吧
Or turn them out altogether.
把它们通通关掉
No scented candles. Okay, here. There we go.
没有精油蜡烛 好吧，我们上吧
Okay, okay. Making me sterile, but okay.
好吧 我没有心情，但没关系
Okay. I'm sorry. Oh, wait. Do we have a condom?
对不起，等一下 我们有保险套吗？
Oh, right!
对了
Yes,98.6. You're gonna be fine.
98点6度，你会没事的
This is it!
就是这里
-That's him! -Great. Go get him!
-就是他 -太棒了，去找他吧
Wait a second. Or maybe you could go in first.
等一下 或许你该先进去
He's not really my type.
他真的不是我喜欢的那一型
Not you. Dr. Ramoray. Ask him questions and see what he's like.
不是你，拉莫瑞医生 问他问题，看看他是什么样的人
-People tell doctors everything. -You said he was this great guy.
-大家会对医生说出所有事 -你说他是个好男人
All the guys I meet seem nice at first, then turn out to be big jerks.
我认识的男人一开始都很好 最后都成了大混蛋
-You do attract some stinkers. -Yeah, I know.
-你的确吸引了一些烂男人 -对，我知道
Dr. Long, I've been at this for 17 hours.
朗医生 我已经等了17个小时
Three women have come and gone with their babies.
三个女人被推进来 又被推出去生下了孩子
You gotta give me good news. How many centimeters am I dilated? Eight? Nine?
你得给我好消息 我张开了几公分？八？九？
-Three. -Just three?
-三 -只有三公分？
I'm dilated three!
我才张开了三公分
We are moving along just slowly. Don't worry, you're doing great.
虽然进度有点慢 放心，你做的很好
-I'll be back soon. -Thank you.
-我马上回来 -谢谢
You know what? I'm not waiting. I'm gonna push this baby out.
你知道吗？我不等 我要把孩子生出来
I'm doing it. Three centimeters. That's gotta be like this, right?
我要那么做，三公分 大概是这么大吧？
-Actually, it's more like this. -Oh, stupid metric system.
-事实上是这么大 -愚蠢的度量衡系统
We're gonna need to take you straight to the delivery room.
我们得直接将你推到产房
Oh, for the love of God!
我的天啊
It's coming! It's coming!
孩子要出来了
And here it is!
她生了
Oh, come on!
天啊
I'm Dr. Drake Ramoray. I have a few routine questions I need to ask you.
我是德瑞克拉莫瑞医生 我得问你几个例行的问题
Really? I've been dealing with Dr. Wells.
真的吗？一直是威尔斯医生在治疗我
I know. I'm a neurologist. Just to be on the safe side..
我是说，我是神经科医生 为了预防万一…
Dr. Wells wanted a more comprehensive overview. So he sent me.
威尔斯医生需要更多相关资料 所以他请我过来
Dr. Wells is a woman!
威尔斯医生是女的
That was a test. Good response.
我是在考你，反应不错
-All right. Full name? -Clifford Burnett.
-好吧，全名 -克利夫伯奈特
-Date of birth? -November 16,1968.
-生日 -1968年11月16日
Age?
年龄
-Can't you figure that out? -I'm a doctor, not a mathematician.
-你不会自己算吗？ -我是医生，不是数学家
-I'm 33. -Okay.
-33岁 -好吧
-And are you married? -No.
-已婚吗？ -不
Oh, really? So 33 and single? Would you say you have commitment issues?
真的吗？33岁还是单身？ 你害怕许下承诺？
Are all the questions this personal?
所有的问题都是私人问题吗？
Yes.
对
Well, if you must know, I'm a widower.
如果你想知道的话，我是鳏夫
-Oh, that's terrible. I'm really sorry. -Yeah.
-太可怕了，我真的很遗憾 -对
I lost my wife five years ago to a mild cardial infarction.
我太太五年前 因为轻度心肌梗塞过世
-A heart attack, doctor. -Oh, yeah. Well, yeah, mild car..
-她得了心脏病，医生 -对，轻度心…
Are you experiencing any dizziness?
你会头晕吗？
No.
不会
-Has the pain been getting worse? -No.
-疼痛有加剧吗？ -没有
Do you sleep with women and never call them again?
你会跟女人上了床后 不再打电话给她们吗？
-No. -Excellent. Excellent.
-不会 -太棒了
And finally, are you into any weird stuff, you know, sexually?
最后是 你有奇怪的性癖好吗？
-No! -Wrong answer.
-没有 -答错了
-This room's available. -Okay! Wait, you listen to me!
-这个房间是空的 -好吧，等一下，听我说
Since I have been waiting, four women..
已经有四个女人…
that's four, one higher than the number of centimeters I'm dilated..
一共是四个 比我子宫颈张开的公分数还多一个
have come and gone with their babies. I'm next. It's my turn. It's only fair.
进来这里，又被推出去生孩子 下一个是我，轮到我了，那才公平
If you bring in one more woman who has her baby before me, I will sue you.
如果你再推个女人进来 她又比我先生，我要告你
Not this hospital. I'm gonna sue you. My husband is a lawyer.
不是这家医院，我要告你 我先生是律师
-Rach? -You get back on that case, honey!
-瑞秋 -你别管这件事
I don't think the next patient is very far along.
我想下一位产妇 不会太快生
Okay. Well, then bring her in.
好吧，把她推进来
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
I can't believe this!
我不敢相信
And yet, somehow, it's true.
但这是真的
I mean, this is so great. We're gonna be baby buddies!
我是说这太棒了 我们可以指腹为婚
Squeeze your legs together and cover the baby's ears.
把你的双腿并拢 别让宝宝听见了
-Hi, sweetie! -Hi, sweetheart.
-嗨，甜心 -嗨，甜心
This is my husband, Sid. I don't think you've met him. Ross, Rachel, this is Sid.
他是我丈夫希德，你们应该没见过他 罗斯，瑞秋，他是希德
I nabbed him a year ago at the dermatologist's office.
一年前我在皮肤科诊所 认识他
Thank God for adult acne!
还好我长了成人型青春痘
I still can't believe it. I'm the luckiest guy in the world.
我还是不敢相信 我是全世界最幸运的人
Really?
真的吗？
What'd he say?
他说什么？
You have to speak very loudly, he's almost completely deaf.
你得大声一点 他几乎快聋了
-Oh, there you go. -Of course he is.
-没错 -那当然
Congratulations, you two. I didn't even know you got married.
恭喜你们 我不知道你们结婚了
-Oh, we didn't. -What?
-我们没结婚 -什么？
We're just having this baby together, but that's all, you know.
我们只是要生下我们的孩子 就是那样
Why?
为什么？
We're just not in that place, you know? But we're very excited about this.
我们还没有到那个程度，知道吗？ 但我们很期待宝宝的出生
Oh. Well, then shut me up.
那样我就没话说了
Just tell me how.
告诉我我该怎么做
Oh, I feel another one coming.
我又开始阵痛了
Sid, you lucky, deaf bastard.
希德，你这个幸运的聋子
-What else? What else? -He's 33.
-还有呢？ -他33岁
A widower.
是个鳏夫
He seemed like a standup guy. And he's not into anything weird sexually.
他似乎是个标准男人 他没有奇怪的性癖好
Enter Phoebe!
菲比要出马了
Should we tell Rachel there's an empty private room right next door to hers?
我们该告诉瑞秋 她隔壁就有一间单人待产室吗？
We could. Or we could have sex in it.
没错，或许我们可以在这里做爱
Well, let me think about that while I remove my pants!
让我边脱裤子边想
Okay, mister! Fertilize me!
好吧，先生，来吧
Does that sound like Janice?
那是珍妮丝的声音吗？
If it's not, then there's two of them.
如果不是的话，就是有个人很像她
And that would mean it's the end of the world!
那表示世界末日到了
Hey.
嘿
-Hey. -Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
I can't believe this is taking so long. How you doing?
我不敢相信要这么久 你还好吗？
Not bad. You know that feeling, trying to blow a Saint Bernard out your ass?
还不错，你知道试着 将圣柏纳犬从屁股推出来的感觉吗？
And soon someone will call her "Mom."
很快会有人叫她“妈”
Weirdest thing. Did I hear..?
真的太奇怪了，我听到…
Mother of God, it's true!
天啊，是真的
Chandler Bing!
钱德宾
Janice.
珍妮丝
Not just Janice. Janice in labor. Contracting and everything.
不只那样，珍妮丝要生了 她正在阵痛
Oh, this should be easy. I have a very wide pelvis.
这应该很容易 我的骨盆很宽
You remember, Chandler.
你应该记得，钱德
I feel so bad for you.
我为你感到难过
She's your ex. And I have Richard.
她是你的前女友，我前男友是理查
Janice, I didn't even know you were pregnant.
珍妮丝 我不知道你怀孕了
Who's the unwitting human whose essence you've stolen?
你偷走了哪个笨蛋的心？
It's you.
这是你的孩子
This is yours.
What?
什么？
Look how nervous he gets! We haven't slept together in years!
看他有多紧张 我们好几年没上过床了
That's funny. Does it hurt? Does the labor hurt?
那真的很有趣，会痛吗？ 生产会痛吗？
Okay, I've got one for you. If you had to, which would you eat?
好吧，我想到一个 如果非吃不可，你要吃哪一个？
A Seeing Eye dog or a talking gorilla?
千里眼的小狗或会说话的猩猩？
I'd have to say the talking gorilla.
我猜是会说话的猩猩
Because at least I could explain to him that you're making me eat him.
因为至少我可以跟他解释 是你逼我吃掉他
-Oh. Somebody went to college. -Yeah.
-有人念过大学 -对
Wow. What is it? I'm sorry.
怎么了？对不起
I'm sorry. My foot itches like crazy.
对不起，我的脚好痒
Oh. I'll get it.
让我来吧
I usually get to know a girl better before I let her spoon me.
通常我会跟女人混熟后 才会让她用汤匙帮我搔痒
Relax. It's not like we're forking.
别激动，它不是叉子
When. When.
太棒了
Thank you. Listen.
谢谢，听着
You seem to really know what to do with a utensil.
你一定是个汤匙高手
Would you like to go to dinner sometime?
你愿意跟我共进晚餐吗？
-Yeah, I'd really like that. -Yeah?
-我很乐意 -是吗？
Yeah. And I promise I won't make you eat any remarkable animals.
对，我发誓不会逼你吃聪明的动物
I was thinking..
我在想…
I'd kind of like to make a move.
我想追求你
But, you know, with the leg.
但我的腿不方便
Oh, yeah.
对
Maybe a little help.
或许需要一点帮忙
Okay.
好吧
Let me fix your pillow.
我来帮你拉枕头
Cliff, you're so forward.
克利夫，你太猴急了
Oh, it was really nice meeting you.
很高兴认识你们
Sid!
希德
That's the first time I heard her voice.
那是我第一次听到她的声音
I didn't care for it.
我不在乎
Oh, that's five, Ross. Five women have had five babies..
一共是五个，罗斯 五个女人生了五个孩子…
and I have had no babies.
我还是没生
Why doesn't she want to come out?
她为什么不肯出来？
You know what I think it is? I think you made such a nice home for her..
你知道我在想什么吗？ 我想九个月来…
over the last nine months that she just doesn't want to leave.
她在你的身体里很舒服 所以她不想离开
Oh, look at you making up crap for me.
你甚至在瞎掰哄我
-Oh, God. -Okay. Okay.
-天啊 -好吧
Twenty-one hours. You're a hero.
21小时，你是英雄
Doctor, you gotta do something! Get me drugs..
医生，你得想想办法 给我药…
or light a fire up in there and just smoke it out!
或是放火 把她薰出来
Actually, I think you're ready to go to the delivery room.
事实上 我想你可以进产房了
What?
什么？
Ten centimeters. You're about to become a mom.
开了10公分了 你快当妈妈了
Oh, my God. Okay.
天啊，好吧
Beat you, sucker! Oh, baby.
打败你了，混蛋，宝贝
Is this the same spoon that was in my cast?
这是刚刚你拿来 帮我搔痒的汤匙吗？
You know what?
你知道吗？
This one is.
这根才是
Oh, my God! That's the doctor who was in my room before.
天啊 他就是刚刚来看过我的医生
Well, it must be one of those closed-circuit hospital channels.
那一定是医院里的 闭路电视系统
No, no. That's a soap opera.
不，那是肥皂剧
This is a very dramatic hospital.
这是家充满戏剧性的医院
I'm telling you, the guy from that show was here..
我是说 电视里的那个人刚刚来过…
asking me all these weird questions.
还问了我一些怪问题
Okay, Mr. Percocet.
好吧，幻想先生
I swear to you, that's the guy.
我发誓就是他
Okay, Cliff.
好吧，克利夫
Do you really believe that a character from a TV show was here in your room?
你真的相信电视明星 来过你的房间？
What probably happened was you were watching this, you drifted off to sleep..
很可能是你在看电视 结果睡着了…
and you dreamt he was here.
你梦到他来过这里
Rachel's having her baby!
瑞秋要生了
Which is of no interest to me as a neurologist. I..
身为神经科医生的我 没有兴趣，我…
That's him! You know him?
就是他，你认识他？
Wake up, Cliff!
醒一醒，克利夫
What is going on?
发生了什么事？
Okay. Okay. I.. Okay.
好吧，我…好吧
I sent my friend, Joey, in here to find out stuff about you.
我派我朋友乔伊 来调查你
If it.. You know, if it helps, you came off great.
如果…如果你想知道的话 我们觉得你是个好人
A lot better than I'm coming off right now.
比现在的我好多了
I don't believe this. You got him to pretend he was a fake doctor?
我不敢相信 你要他假扮医生？
Fake? Excuse me? Hello?
假扮？对不起，哈
-You tried making me think I was crazy? -That was wrong. I'm so sorry.
-你要我以为自己疯了？ -那是不对的，我非常抱歉
It's just that I liked you so much. Can we just start over?
那只是因为我非常喜欢你 我们能重新开始吗？
I don't think so.
我不那么认为
If I may? You told me a lot of personal stuff about you, right?
我可以说话吗？ 你跟我透露了很多你的私事
Now, maybe it would help if you knew some personal stuff about her.
或许你应该知道 一些关于她的私事
She was married to a gay ice dancer.
她曾跟男同志冰舞选手结婚
She gave birth to her brother's triplets.
她帮她弟弟 生下三胞胎
Her twin sister used to do porn.
她的双胞胎姐姐是A片女优
-We're trying to dial down the crazy. -Right.
-我们不想听那些疯狂的事 -对
We don't really know each other, so it'd be easy to forget about this..
我们并不认识彼此 要忘了这些很容易…
but there's something between us. I don't know about you..
但我们对彼此有感觉 我不知道你是怎么样…
but that doesn't happen to me a lot.
但我不是常常遇到这种事
-It doesn't happen to me either. -Me neither!
-我也是 -我也是
-The baby! Rachel! -Right, right!
-瑞秋要生了 -对
Oh, I love this scene.
我喜欢这场戏
Okay, look. I gotta go too.
听着，我也得走了
But.. What do you say? Can we just have that dinner?
但…你觉得呢？ 我们能一起吃晚餐吗？
The triplets.
三胞胎
You and your brother didn't..?
你跟你弟弟没有…
No! No, they implanted embryos.
不，他们植入了胚胎
-Then dinner sounds great. -Great! Okay.
-那么我们可以去吃晚餐 -太棒了
All right, then I'll see you later.
好吧，待会见
Our friend's having a baby.
我们的朋友要生了
-Her own? -Oh, yeah. Yeah.
-那是她自己的孩子？ -对
No, she's really old-fashioned.
不，她真的很传统
Push. Push. We're gonna push for five more seconds.
用力 你得再用力推五秒
Five, four..
五，四…
Three, two, one! Oh!
三，二，一
The next contraction should be in about 20 seconds.
下一次阵痛 是20秒后
-I can't push anymore! -You're doing great.
-我没办法再用力了 -你表现的很好
Oh, God! Twenty seconds, my ass!
天啊，还要20秒耶
Here we go. Okay, keep pushing.
来吧，继续用力
-Come on. -Push. Wait.
-来吧 -推，等一下
-I see something. -What, you do? You do? Oh, my God!
-我看到东西了 -什么？真的吗？我的天啊
-Don't say "Oh, my God!" What?! -What is that?
-别说“我的天啊”，什么？ -那是什么？
The baby's buttocks. She's breech.
宝宝的屁股，她倒过来了
-I thought she had two heads. -Oh, God!
-我以为她有两个头 -天啊
Is she gonna be okay?
她没事吧？
-She's gonna be fine. -Okay.
-她没事的 -好吧
She's in a more difficult position, so you have to push harder now.
她的胎位不正 你得更用力推
-Okay. -That's it. Push. Push.
-好吧 -就是那样，推
You're gonna have to push even harder.
你得更用力推
-I'm sorry, I can't! I can't! -Yes, you can. I know you can do this.
-抱歉，我办不到 -不，我知道你办得到
I had no idea. Please, you do it for me!
我不知道 拜托，帮我推吧
Let's go. One more time. One final push. Ready? One, two, three.
来吧，再一次 最后一次，准备好了吗？一，二，三
Good.
很好
Keep pushing!
继续用力
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
You have no idea how much this hurts.
你不知道那有多痛
Keep going! Keep going!
继续用力
Here we go!
好了
She's upside down, but she's coming!
宝宝胎位不正，但她要出来了
-Oh, God! -Oh! Oh, my God!
-天啊 -我的天啊
Oh, my God, she's here.
天啊，她出来了
Oh, she's perfect.
她太完美了
Oh, wow! Oh, she's so tiny.
哇，她好小
-Where'd she go? -They're just wrapping her up.
-她要去哪里？ -他们得先把她包起来
Okay. Well, be careful with her, she's really tiny.
好吧，小心一点 她真的很小
Here she is.
来吧
Oh, thanks for coming out of me.
谢谢你终于出来了
I know. Oh.
我知道
She's looking at me. Hi. I know you.
她在看我，嗨，我认识你
-Do we have a name yet? -No, not yet.
-你们取好名字了吗？ -还没有
That's fine. For now we'll just call her Baby Girl Greene.
没关系 先叫她葛林之女
Oh, no. Baby Girl Geller-Greene.
不，盖勒葛林之女
Hello, Baby Girl.
嗨，小女孩
-Can we come in? -Oh, come on in.
-我们能进去吗？ -请进
-Oh, there she is. -Oh, she's so beautiful.
-她在那里 -她好漂亮
Here.
来吧
Oh, my God. She's amazing.
天啊，她好神奇
Oh, I'm so glad you guys got drunk and had sex.
我很高兴 你们喝醉后上了床
It's incredible. I mean, one minute she's inside you..
太不可思议了 前一分钟她还在你肚子里…
and then 47 hours later, here she is.
47小时后她就出现了
She looks so real.
她看起来好真实
You know what I mean.
你们了解我的意思
She's this whole tiny little person.
她是个小宝贝
And she already has eyelashes and knees and..
她已经有眼睫毛 膝盖跟…
-What? -Oh, no, no. It's okay.
-什么？ -不，没事
For a second, I counted six fingers, but one was from the other hand. So we're good.
刚刚我以为她有六根手指 但有一根是另一只手的，没事
-Okay, my turn. My turn. -Aunt Phoebe.
-好了，轮到我了 -菲比阿姨
Oh, baby. Oh, you're so cute!
宝贝，你好可爱
Oh, I could squeeze your little head.
我可以捏碎你小小的头
I won't.
我不会那么做的
-Honey, what's the matter? -Nothing. I just can't stop crying.
-甜心，怎么了？ -没事，我只是不由自主地哭了
The doctor said it's normal, with all the hormones, plus you're sleep-deprived.
医生说这很正常 都是荷尔蒙害的，而且我还会睡不着
So. You guys are all sleep-deprived.
你们都会失眠
I don't see you weeping because you put your slippers on the wrong feet.
我没看过你因为鞋子穿错脚 就哭个不停
Oh, God.
天啊
-What's the matter now? -I was reliving it.
-怎么了？ -我又想起来了
Do you know what you're gonna call her yet?
你们帮她 取好名字了吗？
Wait, it's not gonna be Baby Girl? I thought that was so original.
等一下，她不是叫宝宝女吗？ 我觉得那个名字很有创意
Actually, we've narrowed it down to two names.
事实上 我们正在考虑两个名字
And you know what? I love them both. So just pick one, and that'll be it.
你知道吗？两个名字我都很喜欢 你们帮忙挑一个
Wow, okay. Everyone..
好吧，大伙们…
this is lsabella.
她是伊莎贝儿
-Hi, lsabella! -Hi.
-嗨，伊莎贝儿 -嗨
What?
什么？
That's not her name.
那不是她的名字
I'm sorry, she just doesn't feel like an lsabella.
抱歉 她感觉上不像伊莎贝儿
So then I guess Ferdinand is out.
我猜佛迪南出局了
-What was the other one? -Delilah.
-另一个名字是什么？ -笛莉拉
Oh, great! Suddenly she sounds like a biblical whore.
太棒了 突然间她成了圣经里的妓女
So I guess we're back to Baby Girl.
我猜还是叫她宝宝女吧
What are we gonna do?
我们该怎么办？
-It's okay. You'll find a name. -Easy for you to say.
-没关系，你们会想到好名字的 -你说的倒容易
You already know what your kids' names will be.
你已经知道 你的孩子要叫什么名字了
-You do? -I had them picked out since I was 14.
-是吗？ -我14岁时就帮他们取好了名字
Oh, no, it's gonna be named after some snack or baked good, isn't it?
不，你的宝宝会以点心 或烘烤食物的名字来命名吧？
-Well, tell us, what are they? -Okay. If it's a boy, it's Daniel.
-告诉我们你想了什么名字 -好吧，如果是男孩的话就叫丹尼尔
-And if it's a girl? -I don't wanna say.
-如果是女孩呢？ -我不想说
Oh, stop. Tell us. We're not gonna want it.
少来了，告诉我们 我们不会抢走它的
Okay. It's Emma.
好吧，她叫艾犸
Emma.
艾犸
See, I don't want it.
看吧，我不喜欢它
Do you have any other totally perfect names that you're not gonna use?
你还想到其他你不会用的 完美名字吗？
-Take it. -What?
-拿去吧 -什么？
She's clearly an Emma.
她真的很适合叫艾犸
Oh, honey, but you love that name.
甜心，但你喜欢那个名字
Yeah, but I love you more.
对，但我更爱你
Besides, nothing goes with Bing. So I'm screwed.
而且什么名字都跟宾不配 所以我是死定了
Hi, Emma.
嗨，艾犸
Yep, that's you.
对，就是你
You're our little Em.
你是我们的小艾犸
What's that, honey?
怎么了？甜心
What?
什么？
Oh, you want a little cousin?
你要个小表妹？
You want a cousin right now?
你现在就要？
Do I look like a giant sperm to all of you, or..?
你们觉得 我看起来像个大精子或…
（清洁间）
-That was amazing. -I know.
-那真的是太神奇了 -我知道
Hey, do you realize that we may have just changed our lives forever?
你知道我们很可能 已经永远地改变了我们的生活吗？
We may have started our family. In nine months we could be here..
我们可能已经开始组成了我们的家庭 九个月后我们可能会来这里…
having our own baby.
生下我们的孩子
And if not, we got to do it on a bucket.
要是没办法的话 我们得把宝宝生在桶里
I love you so much.
我非常爱你
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
-是吗？ -对
You wanna do it again?
你想再做一次吗？
This time just for us?
这次是为了我们？
Probably.
或许吧
Aaron Lipman-Guralnick would like to say hello to his future bride.
亚朗利普曼古拉尼克 要跟他未来的新娘打个招呼
Wow, he kind of takes your breath away, doesn't he?
他真的会让人说不出话来 对吧？
He's a keeper.
他是个谦虚的人
Look at the little munchkin.
看看那个小可爱
Don't you worry. By the time you're old enough to date him..
别担心 当你大到可以跟他约会时…
he's gonna have a different nose.
他会有个不一样的鼻子
-How you feeling? -Oh, I'm fine.
-你觉得如何？ -我很好
I really admire what you're doing. Just raising her all alone.
我真的很佩服你做的事 你要自己抚养她
I'm not doing it alone. I have Ross.
我不是一个人，我有罗斯
Sure. Now. But what happens when he meets somebody else and gets married?
现在是的，如果他认识别人结了婚 那时又会是怎么样的呢？
Well, then he gets a divorce. It's Ross.
他会离婚的 那就是罗斯
I'm telling you, Rachel, listen to Janice.
我得告诉你，瑞秋，听珍妮丝的话
They all say they're gonna be there, until they start their real family.
男人都说他们会在 但他们会成立自己的家庭
-That's never gonna happen with Ross. -That's what I thought.
-罗斯不会那么做的 -以前我也那么相信
I'm lucky if my kid gets to spend a weekend with her father..
如果我的孩子能跟她爸 及新的波霸小姐共度一个周末…
and little Miss New Boobs.
那算我运气好
Really?
真的吗？
I hate to be the one to say it..
我讨厌跟你这么说…
but, honey, you two are on your own.
但你们两个得靠自己
Well, that's.. You know, that's..
那是…你知道的，那是…
We've been alone for the last 20 minutes and we're doing okay.
我们已经单独相处了20分钟 我们表现的很好
Maybe we won't be alone.
或许我们不会孤单的
Because lately things have been happening between me and Ross.
因为最近 我跟罗斯之间有些事发生
And right before I went into labor, we had this kiss. You know?
我来医院前 我们还接了吻，你知道吗？
So it might be the beginning of something.
或许那会是个开始
-Hey, Janice. -Oh, hi.
-嗨，珍妮丝 -嗨
Who's this little guy?
这个小家伙是谁？
-Aaron, your future son-in-law. -Oh, no, no.
-亚朗，那是你未来的岳父 -不
No.
不
-I'm gonna leave you three alone. -Okay.
-我让你们一家人好好独处 -好吧
Man, you see the kid on that nose?
天啊，你看到那孩子的鼻子了吗？
You know what I was thinking about?
你知道我刚刚想到什么吗？
That kiss before we left the apartment. That was something, huh?
我们出门前的那个吻 那真的很特别吧？
Yeah. Yeah, it really was.
对，真的是
But we.. We gotta be careful.
但我们…我们得小心点
We.. You know, we can't let that happen again, you know?
我们…你知道的 我们不能让历史重演
Right.
对
-We don't want to go down that road. -No. That's why I brought it up.
-我们不希望再发生那种事 -对，所以我才会跟你提这件事
-They didn't have any sodas? -Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
-他们没有汽水吗？ -天啊，对不起
I was talking to this nurse. Completely forgot.
我忙着跟护士说话 完全忘了
And so it begins.
现在就已经开始了
She in there?
她在里面吗？
Yeah. She's putting her down now. That's her.
对，护士正把她放在床上 那就是她
Isn't it amazing how every baby is beautiful?
每个宝宝都很漂亮 那真的很神奇吧？
Except that one.
除了那个以外
What is this? A petting zoo?
这是什么？宠物动物园吗？
Look. Look at Emma.
你看，快看艾犸
I can't decide who she looks like, you or Rachel.
我无法决定 她长得像你或瑞秋
Oh, what, are you kidding? She's gorgeous! It's all Rachel.
什么？你在开玩笑吗？ 她美极了，完全是瑞秋的遗传
I'm sorry. For the last time, why aren't you two together again?
对不起，这是我最后一次问你 你们两个为什么不结婚？
No, I know. Because you're not in that place.
不，我知道 因为你们没有到那个程度
Which would be fine, except you totally are.
那真的很棒 但事实上你们真的到了
It's complicated, okay?
情况很复杂，好吗？
Yeah, that's true.
对，那是真的
You love her, you always have, you have a child together.
你一直都爱着她 你们生了一个孩子
There's no right answer.
没有答案是百分之百的正确
Look, we've been together. Then apart. Then together, then apart.
我们曾经交往过 后来分手，复合后又分手
And now we have a baby.
现在我们生了一个孩子
It's just, if we got together again and it didn't work out..
如果我们又复合 结果还是不行…
I could never do that to Emma.
我不会对艾犸那么做
I mean, she came into this world thinking everything.. Now me.
她来到这个世界 想像每件事都…这是我的想法
What, do they put something in the water here?
什么？ 他们在水里放东西？
It's just, Rachel and l, we're doing really well now.
瑞秋跟我 现在过得很好
I know. If you try to make it more, you might wreck it.
我知道，如果你想更进一步 就得突破现状
-Yeah, exactly. -Right.
-没错 -对
Or you might get everything you've wanted since you were 15.
或许你可以得到 你从15岁开始梦想的世界
Hey.
嘿
I saw a woman breast-feeding twins at the same time.
我看到一个女人 同时在喂双胞胎母乳
It is like a freak show up here.
那真的很像怪物秀
-What's the matter? -Nothing.
-怎么了？ -没事
What is it? Hey.
怎么了？嘿
-Really, it's nothing. I'm.. -Rach, come on. What?
-真的没事，我… -瑞秋，别这样，什么？
I've just been thinking about how my baby and I are gonna be all alone.
我一直在想 我跟宝宝要怎么独自活下去
What are you talking about? What about Ross?
你在说什么？罗斯呢？
Please. He'll be with his real family. The twins and little Miss New Boobs.
拜托，他会有自己的家庭 双胞胎跟新波霸小姐
Okay, how long was I watching that woman?
好吧 我看那个女人多久了？
I'm just saying that, you know..
我那么说…
someday Ross is gonna meet somebody..
因为有一天 罗斯会认识别人…
and he's gonna have his own life.
他会去过自己的生活
Right?
对吧？
Yeah, I guess so.
我猜你说的对
I just never thought I'd be raising this baby all by myself.
我没有想过 我要自己抚养这个宝宝
That's pretty dumb, huh?
那真的很傻吧？
Hey, you listen to me. Listen to me.
你得听我说，听着
You are never, ever gonna be alone.
你永远都不会是一个人
Okay? I promise I won't let that happen.
好吧？ 我发誓我不会让那种事发生
Joey. Oh, sweetie, what would I do without you?
乔伊，喔，甜心 没有你我该怎么办？
You don't have to worry about that, okay?
你不必担心，好吗？
Could you grab me my other box of tissues?
你能再帮我 拿盒面纸来吗？
-They're under Ross' coat. -Sure.
-就在罗斯的外套下面 -没问题
Oh, my God!
我的天啊
Joey?
乔伊
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Okay.
好吧